### **Howard Jess**

### Web Application UI/UX Developer

hjess@mail.com linkedin.com/in/hjess 206.412.9924

### **Brief**

I thrive in a collaborative team environment; after experience with desktop applications, system programming, and networking infrastructure, I settled into web application UI development as an interesting intersection. I'm especially interested in user experience and accessibility. In a team setting, I am highly-collaborative, and offer excellent communication and creative problem solving skills.

#### Skills

Languages: Javascript, Typescript, HTML, CSS (Less, SASS/SCSS)

UI Technologies: Bootstrap, Element UI, DOM, HTTP, i18n/l10n, jQuery, Knockout, MVC,

REST, TCP/IP, Vue.js

Tools: Bourne shell, GIMP, Git, npm, VIM

Systems: Linux, Unix, Mac OS/X, Windows

Development: <u>Agile, Scrum, Kanban</u>

# **Professional Experience**

**Trupanion** April 2017 → June 2023

Javascript, Typescript, Vue, SCSS, CSS, Bootstrap, HTML, Razor (C# templates), SignalR, ASP.Net, Git

Trupanion's first dedicated UI specialist. Projects:

- <u>VetPortal</u> (lead UI dev): cut payload by 50%, decreasing server load and client load time, in a full rewrite of vet hospital software.
- Hospital Management Tool (sole UI dev): created a VetPortal support app, reducing support staff paperwork and load.
- Member Portal (lead UI dev): developed member access application *v2*; reduced customer phone support load by 70%.
- Partner Portal (sole UI dev): revamped web app for State Farm agents to create and manage policies; increased policy sales by as much as 1%.
- Agent Reassignment Tool (sole UI dev): invented web app for State Farm managers to manage agent policy assignments, reducing paperwork by 50%.
- Website 3.0: consulted/mentored the rewrite team Trupanion's public-facing website.

## Navigating Cancer (contract position)

June 2016 → February 2017

Bootstrap, Coffeescript, Backbone.js, HAML, JSON Schema, JSON Editor, Mocha, Ruby on Rails, SASS

Developer for Navigating Cancer's suite of Patient Care Management software, dedicated to improving and streamlining the relationship and care experience for cancer patients and oncology clinics. Projects:

- Complex Triage Pathways: implemented <u>JSON Schema</u>+<u>JSON Editor</u>-based live forms to standardize symptom data recording; reduced clinic tech training load by 50% (or so).
- <u>Living Style Guide</u>: continued work to maintain and upgrade the style and component library document; lowered developer support cost by 30% (best guess).

### **Howard Jess**

### Web Application UI/UX Developer

hjess@mail.com linkedin.com/in/hjess 206.412.9924

Rosetta Stone (acquired Livemocha in April 2013)

November 2012 → April 2016

AngularJS, CouchDB, HTML, Javascript, Mixpanel, SCSS, Sproutcore

Developer for Rosetta Stone's <u>Advanced English for Business</u> language-learning application, and <u>Livemocha</u>, a social community-based language-learning application. Projects:

- Full language-learning engine rewrite from <u>Sproutcore</u> to <u>AngularJS</u>; reduced network payload and latencies by over 50% (estimate), increased ease-of-learning/ease-of-use.
- Password reset/recovery: simplified components to reduce developer maintenance responsibilities by 25% (another guess).
- User profile management: streamlined back-office maintenance tasks.
- Partner connections: created application links to 3rd-party partners, increasing visibility by 30% (guesstimate).
- Analytics, using Mixpanel: supported enhanced BI/BA.

**Optify** 

September 2011 → October 2012

Backbone.js, HTML, Javascript, LESS, Mixpanel

UI developer for Optify's *Inbound Marketing* software suite, a <u>SAAS</u> tool for B2B marketers. Projects:

- Developed a site "Landing Page" editor/publisher, for 100% hands-off customer use.
- Authored and updated Contact Manager and Email Manager tools.
- Designed and built analytics, using <u>Mixpanel</u> providing 100% more application instrumentation visibility.
- Updated and enhanced UI coding standards document, and overhauled the Javascript library namespace.

# **CDK Global** (formerly Cobalt)

September 2009 → September 2011

Lead UI developer on Cobalt's *New Products* team, charged with creating and delivering innovative website products for sale to auto manufacturers and dealers. Projects:

- Authored embedded Google maps for location pages.
- Built <u>Facebook</u> and <u>Twitter</u> publishing and <u>feed</u> widgets.
- Produced embedded <u>YouTube</u> player/playlist handler.
- Started front-end unit testing using jstestdriver.

### **Education**

**Northwestern University** 

B.A., Economics